Guide to the New York University Archives Collection of Minutes MC.346
New York University Archives
New York University Archives Collection of Minutes
1832-2016
New York University Archives
MC.346
72.7 Linear Feet in 143 manuscript boxes, 41 half manuscript boxes, and 3 flat boxes
The New York University Archives Collection of Minutes was created by the University Archives to group together minutes documenting meetings of various university entities. Groups represented in this collection include the University Senate; university officers; the medical, dental, education, professional, and engineering schools; the College of Arts and Sciences; and the Student Council. Material dates from 1832 to 2016.
Scope and Contents
The New York University Archives Collection of Minutes consists of minutes documenting meetings of various university entities, from the University Senate to departmental or school faculty minutes to the minutes of the Student Council. Material dates from 1832 to 2016.
Historical Note
The New York University Archives Collection of Minutes was created by the University Archives to group together minutes documenting meetings of various university entities.
Arrangement
The collection is arranged by record group number.
Conditions Governing Access
Material pertaining to individual student records may be restricted in accordance with the Family Educational Rights and Privacy Act (FERPA). Please contact the Archives with specific questions regarding access to such records.
Administrative records and unpublished reports of New York University are closed for a period of 20 years from the date of their creation. Access to files spanning multiple years will be opened to researchers based on the date of the most recent materials. Board of Trustees records are closed for 35 years from the date of creation. Materials related to personnel, grievances, job and fellowship searches and applications, and all files that fall under the federal Family Educational Rights and Privacy Act (FERPA) are permanently restricted. Additional restrictions may apply to other materials in this collection. For questions regarding specific restrictions, please contact the University Archives.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Some materials in this collection were transferred from various New York University departments between 1981 and 2009. No information was recorded about the acquisition of the other materials in this collection. The accession numbers associated with these transfers include 09.016, 81.033, 91.003, and 91.004.
Minutes (administrative records); College administrators -- United States
- All-University, RG 1, Undated
  - Faculty Club, Undated (Box 135)
- Board of Trustees (Council), RG 2, 1976-1979
  - Senate Financial Affairs Committee, 1976-1979 (Box 130)
- Office of the President/Chancellor, RG 3, 1952-1973
  - President and Deans Meetings Minutes, 1974-1977 (Box 133)
  - Assistants (Executive and Special) to President: Officers' Group, Administrative Staff, 1952-1968 (Box 138)
  - Assistants (Executive and Special) to President: Officers' Group, Administrative Staff, 1968-1975 (Box 139)
  - Presidential Commissions, Committees, Task Forces, Advisory Groups: Presidents Council on the Graduate School of Arts and Science, 1965-1973 (Box 140)
- Office of the Vice President of External Affairs, RG 7, Undated
  - Minutes, Undated (Box 122)
- Medical Center, RG 13, 1966-2000
  - Board of Trustees Minutes, 1966-1968 (Box 123)
  - Board of Trustees Minutes, 1968-1970 (Box 124)
  - Board of Trustees Minutes, 1983-1985 (Box 125)
  - Board of Trustees Minutes, 1983-1984 (Box 126)
  - Board of Trustees Minutes, 1984-1985 (Box 127)
  - Board of Trustees Minutes, 1985-1986 (Box 128)
  - Board of Trustees Minutes, 1970-1972 (Box 129)
  - Board of Trustees Minutes, 1986-1989 (Box 131)
  - Board of Trustees Minutes, 1972-1974 (Box 132)
  - Board of Trustees Minutes, 1974-1976 (Box 134)
  - Board of Trustees Minutes, Council of Departmental Chairmen Minutes, 1975-1976 (Box 137)
  - Board of Trustees Minutes, 1977-1980 (Box 141)
  - Board of Trustees Minutes, 1981-1982 (Box 142)
  - Board of Trustees Minutes, 1983-1983 (Box 143)
  - Board of Trustees Minutes, 1991-1995 (Box 144)
  - Board of Trustees Minutes, 1995-2000 (Box 145)
  - Board of Trustees Minutes, 1989-1990 (Box 146)
  - Board of Trustees Minutes, 1987-1988 (Box 147)
  - Board of Trustees Minutes, 1990-1991 (Box 148)
  - Board of Trustees Minutes, 1988-1989 (Box 149)
  - Board of Trustees Minutes, 1993-1996 (Box 150)
  - Board of Trustees Minutes, 1996-1998 (Box 151)
- University Senate, RG 14, 1897-2010
  - University Senate Minutes, 1975-1975 (Box 152)
  - University Senate Minutes, 1968-1968 (Box 153)
  - University Senate Minutes, 1951-1956 (Box 154)
  - University Senate Minutes, 1976-1977 (Box 155)
  - University Senate Minutes, 1969-1969 (Box 156)
  - University Senate Minutes, 1941-1950 (Box 157)
  - University Senate Minutes, 1957-1963 (Box 158)
  - University Senate Minutes, 1964-1967 (Box 159)
  - University Senate Minutes, 1970-1970 (Box 160)
  - University Senate Minutes, 1970-1971 (Box 161)
  - University Senate Minutes, 1978-1990 (Box 162)
  - University Senate Minutes, 1971-1972 (Box 163)
  - University Senate Minutes, 1897-1940 (Box 164)
  - University Senate Minutes, 1972-1973 (Box 165)
  - University Senate Minutes, 1973-1974 (Box 166)
  - University Senate Minutes, 1990-1997 (Box 174)
  - University Senate Minutes, 1997-2000 (Box 177)
  - University Senate Minutes, 2001-2008 (Box 178)
  - University Senate Minutes, 2009-2010 (Box 179)
  - Senate Commission on Student Participation Minutes, 1966-1967 (Box 180)
  - Faculty Senators Council, 2001-2008 (Box 186)
- University Councils, Commissions, and Committees, RG 15, 1934-2016
  - Minutes, 1972-1975 (Box 136)
  - Washington Square Council Minutes, Committee on Inventions and Patents, 1961-1974 (Box 167)
  - Deans Council Minutes, 1986-1987 (Box 168)
  - Deans Council Minutes, 1984-1986 (Box 169)
  - Deans Council Minutes, 1955-1970 (Box 190)
  - Deans Council Minutes, 1970-1980 (Box 191)
  - University Heights Council Minutes, 1965-1971 (Box 188)
  - Faculty Council Minutes, 1970-1983 (Box 170)
  - Faculty Council Minutes, 1983-1989 (Box 171)
  - Faculty Council Minutes, 1989-1998 (Box 172)
  - Faculty Council Minutes, 1998-2004 (Box 181)
  - Committee on Faculty Promotion Policy; Association of Lesbian and Gay Faculty, Administrators and Staff, 1965, 1992 (Box 182)
  - Commission on Student Life at Washington Square, 1968-1970 (Box 183)
  - Commission on Student Life at Washington Square, 1965-1969 (Box 184)
  - Commission on Student Life at Washington Square, 1965-1967 (Box 189)
  - Administrative Management Council, 1963-1987 (Box 173)
  - Administrative Management Council, 1994-2016 (Box 175)
  - Administrative Management Council, 1987-1994 (Box 176)
  - University Commission on Graduate Work, 1934-1969 (Box 185)
  - University Commission on Graduate Work, 1970-1977 (Box 187)
- University College of Arts and Science, RG 18, 1832-1972
  - Faculty Minutes, 1832-1856 (Box 33)
  - University College Faculty Minutes, 1857-1894 (Box 36)
  - Univeristy College Faculty Minutes, 1894-1925 (Box 37)
  - Index of Faculty Minutes, 1969-1972 (Box 46)
  - Faculty Minutes, 1892-1892 (Box 49)
  - Faculty Minutes, 1956-1972 (Box 50)
- College of Arts and Sciences, RG 19, 1914-1988
  - Faculty Minutes (duplicates), 1943-1959 (Box 48)
  - Faculty Minutes (duplicates), 1960-1967 (Box 51)
  - Advisory Committee Minutes, 1936-1943 (Box 52)
  - Faculty Minutes (duplicates), 1967-1969 (Box 53)
  - Budgetary Unites, 1970-1973 (Box 54)
  - Faculty Minutes (duplicates), 1970-1970 (Box 55)
  - Faculty Minutes, 1914-1953 (Box 56)
  - Faculty Minutes (duplicates), 1971-1988 (Box 57)
  - Faculty Minutes, 1954-1961 (Box 58)
  - Faculty Minutes, 1962-1967 (Box 61)
  - Faculty Minutes, 1968-1970 (Box 66)
  - Faculty Minutes, 1971-1974 (Box 69)
  - Elections and Memoranda, 1965-1974 (Box 60)
- Graduate School of the Arts and Science, RG 20, 1894-2008
  - Faculty Minutes, 1914-1950 (Box 47)
  - Advisory Committee Minutes, 1965-1967 (Box 63)
  - Faculty Minutes, 1894-1914 (Box 65)
  - Faculty Minutes, 1980-1987 (Box 71)
  - Curriculum Committee Minutes, 1983-1983 (Box 72)
  - Faculty Minutes, 1950-1961 (Box 73)
  - Cirriculum Committee Minutes, 1984-1992 (Box 74)
  - Faculty Minutes, 1962-1964 (Box 76)
  - Department of History, Archival Management Program Minutes, Board of Trustees Meeting Minutes IFA, GSAS Research Fund Calendar and Minutes, 1978-2008 (Box 77)
  - Curriculum Committee Minutes, 1950-1965 (Box 78)
  - Faculty Minutes, 1965-1966 (Box 79)
  - Faculty Minutes, 1967-1968 (Box 82)
  - Cirriculum Committee Minutes, 1968-1971 (Box 83)
  - Faculty Minutes, 1969-1970 (Box 84)
  - Faculty Minutes, 1972-1975 (Box 86)
  - Faculty Minutes, 1976-1980 (Box 89)
  - Cirriculum Committee Minutes, 1907-1937 (Box 68)
  - Curriculum Committee Minutes, 1993-1993 (Box 75)
  - Curriculum Committee Minutes, 1965-1968 (Box 81)
  - Curriculum Committee Minutes, 1972-1974 (Box 85)
  - Curriculum Committee Minutes, 1974-1976 (Box 88)
  - Curriculum Committee Minutes, 1982-1982 (Box 90)
  - Group Committee, 1914-1937 (Box 91)
  - Fellowship Committee, 1907-1937 (Box 92)
  - Faculty Minutes, 1987-1995 (Box 113)
- Faculty of Arts and Science, RG 21, 1955-2013
  - Committee of Arts and Science Minutes, 1958-1970 (Box 70)
  - All-University Department Heads Minutes, 1955-1967 (Box 80)
  - Faculty Minutes, 1970-1977 (Box 87)
  - Faculty Minutes, 2012-2013 (Box 96)
  - Faculty Minutes, 1973-1976 (Box 100)
  - Faculty Minutes, 1976-1978 (Box 101)
  - Faculty Minutes, 1978-1980 (Box 106)
  - Faculty Minutes, 1980-1988 (Box 108)
  - Faculty Minutes, 1998-2004 (Box 115)
  - Faculty Minutes, 2004-2012 (Box 117)
- School of Law, RG 22, 1887-1982
  - Faculty Minutes, 1905-1916 (Box 97)
  - Faculty Minutes, 1916-1919 (Box 102)
  - Faculty Minutes, 1977-1982 (Box 103)
  - Faculty Minutes, 1946-1967 (Box 105)
  - Faculty Minutes, 1966-1977 (Box 109)
  - Faculty Minutes, 1968-1974 (Box 110)
  - Graduate Division Executive Committee Minutes, 1974-1981 (Box 111)
  - Faculty Minutes, 1887-1904 (Box 119)
- School of Medicine, RG 23, 1966-1986
  - Council of Departmental Chairmen Minutes, 1976-1986 (Box 98)
  - Steering Committee, 1966-1986 (Box 99)
  - Faculty Council Minutes, 1974-1976 (Box 118)
- School of Engineering and Science, RG 24, 1889-1973
  - Faculty Minutes, 1889-1911 (Box 104)
  - Faculty Minutes, 1968-1973 (Box 120)
- College of Dentistry, RG 25, 1894-1987
  - Faculty Minutes, 1929-1972 (Box 107)
  - Alumni Association, Century Club, Library Committee, General Faculty, Parents Association, 1931-1987 (Box 112)
  - Board of Trustees, Executive Committee, 1894-1904 (Box 121)
- Steinhardt School of Education; School of Education, Health, Nursing, and the Arts Professions, RG 26, 1890-1986
  - Faculty Minutes, 1970-1973 (Box 24)
  - Faculty Minutes, 1974-1974 (Box 25)
  - Faculty Minutes, 1975-1977 (Box 26)
  - Faculty Minutes, 1944-1956 (Box 27)
  - Faculty Minutes, 1923-1944 (Box 28)
  - Faculty Minutes, 1890-1916 (Box 29)
  - Faculty Council Minutes, 1974-1978 (Box 30)
  - Faculty Council Minutes, 1972-1974 (Box 31)
  - Faculty Minutes, 1956-1960 (Box 32)
  - SEHNAP Faculty Minutes, 1960-1965 (Box 38)
  - School of Education Faculty Council Minutes, 1967-1969 (Box 39)
  - Faculty Council Minutes, 1967-1969 (Box 40)
  - Faculty Council Minutes, 1970-1971 (Box 41)
  - Faculty Minutes, 1965-1969 (Box 42)
  - Faculty Minutes, 1980-1983 (Box 43)
  - Faculty Minutes, 1983-1986 (Box 44)
  - Advisory Council Minutes, 1959-1967 (Box 45)
  - Faculty Minutes, 1977-1980 (Box 59)
  - Faculty Council Minutes, 1949-1955 (Box 93)
  - Faculty Council Minutes, 1955-1959 (Box 94)
  - Faculty Council Minutes, 1959-1967 (Box 95)
  - General Committee Minutes, 1925-1939 (Box 114)
  - General Committee Minutes, Faculty Council Minutes, 1939-1950 (Box 116)
- Faculty of Business Administration; School of Business, RG 29, 1968-1982
  - Faculty Minutes, 1968-1982 (Box 64)
- School of Professional Studies, RG 32, 1969-1984
  - Faculty Minutes, 1969-1984 (Box 62)
- Graduate School of Public Administration, RG 33, 1968-1979
  - Faculty Minutes, 1968-1979 (Box 1)
  - Faculty/Student Council Meetings, 1973-1973 (Box 2)
- Silver School of Social Work, RG 34, 1971-1976
  - Faculty Minutes, 1971-1976 (Box 3)
- Tisch School of the Arts, RG 35, 1975-1975
  - Faculty Minutes, 1975-1975 (Box 4)
- Gallatin Division, RG 36, 1977-1977
  - Faculty Minutes, 1977-1977 (Box 5)
- Division of Libraries, RG 38, 1970-2014
  - Society of Libraries, General Assemblies/Meetings, 1971-1971 (Box 6)
  - Depertment and Unit Heads, 1978-1989 (Box 7)
  - Depertment and Unit Heads, 1988-1988 (Box 18)
  - Library Council Minutes, 1981-1990 (Box 8)
  - Library Council Minutes, 1991-2012 (Box 19)
  - Library Council Minutes, 2013-2013 (Box 20)
  - Faculty minutes, 2014-2014 (Box 21)
  - Library Council Minutes, 1970-1974 (Box 34)
  - Library Council Minutes, 1975-1980 (Box 35)
- Huntington Hill Historical Society/ NYU Historical Society, RG 39.10
  - Minutes of the NYU Historical Society, 1910-1918 (Box Shared University Archives 076)
- Alumni Association and Activities, RG 40, 1862-1925
  - Alumni Association, 1862-1925 (Box 23)
- Student Governance, RG 44, 1958-2000
  - Student Senators Council, 2000-2000 (Box 9)
  - University Committee on Student Life Minutes, 1976-1977 (Box 14)
  - Student Senators Council Minutes, 1976-1999 (Box 22)
  - Graduate School Council Minutes, 1969-1982 (Box 10)
  - Student Council Minutes, 1958-1983 (Box 11)
  - Student Council Minutes, 1983-1985 (Box 12)
  - Student Council Minutes, 1985-1987 (Box 13)
- Student Governing Board, RG 44.8, 1958-1968
  - Minutes and Constitutions, 1958-1968 (Box 15)
- Student Life Committee, 1977-2003
  - University Committee on Student Life Minutes, 1992-2003 (Box 16)
  - Minutes of the Meeting of the Audit Subcommittee, 1977-1977 (Box 17)